<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PotterPals</string>
    <string-array name="book_nums">
        <item>Harry Potter and the Sorcerers Stone</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</item>
        <item>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="book1Summ">"Harry Potter lives at Number Four, Privet Drive, in Little Whinging, England with his terrible adoptive family, the Dursleys. The poor orphan lives a mistreated life, living in the cupboard under the stairs. On his 11th birthday, mysterious letters begin to arrive, addressed to Mr. Potter. They are invitations to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Harry learns from the half giant Hagrid that not only is he a wizard, but he's the most famous orphan in the magical world.

Hagrid tells Harry that he received the lightning bolt scar on his forehead after an attack from the Dark Lord Voldemort, ten years earlier. It was during this assault that Harry lost both of his parent. Voldemort lost his powers and disappeared when he was unable to kill Harry. Hagrid takes Harry from his aunt and uncle's and shows him around the wizarding world, through Diagon Alley, a street full of magical shops that is hidden from the non-magical people known as "muggles". Harry learns of the fortune he has inherited at Gringotts Wizarding Bank. After buying books, a uniform and his magic wand, Harry boards the Hogwarts Express at King's Cross railroad station, platfrorm 9 3/4.

On the arrival to Hogwarts, Harry is sorted into the House of Gryffindor, along with his new friends, Ron and Hermione. Draco Malfoy, a boy Harry meets and instantly takes a disliking to, is sorted into the House of Slytherin, the former house of Voldemort. After learning of his natural talent for flying, Harry learns about Quidditch, a soccer-like game played while flying on broomsticks, and becomes the youngest Seeker the Gryffindor team has had in a hundred years.

During the Halloween feast, a troll is found in the dungeon. Harry and Ron save Hermione from the attack, strengthing their friendship. Instead of returning to the Dursleys' for Christmas break, Harry decides to stay at Hogwarts. He stumbles across the Mirror of Erised, which shows the deepest desire of the one who gazes upon it. He sees himself surrounded by his parents and family. He also receives an Invisibility Cloak, a present that will help him out many times to come. After one of their crazy adventures, Harry and Hermione find themself in trouble. As punishment, they must go into the Forbidden Forest with Hagrid to find an injured unicorn. Harry finds a cloaked figure drinking blood from a unicorn. A centaur informs him the cloaked man was none other than Voldemort, trying to maintain his phantom existence.

Harry, Ron and Hermione find out that the legendary Sorcerer's Stone is being guarded by a three-heade dog. They learn that Hagrid told a stranger how to get past the dog. Figuring it's Voldemort that's trying to steal the stone, the trio goes on a courageous adventure to protect it. Using Ron's skill of chess, Harry's skill of flying and Hermione's magical knowledge, Harry finds himself faced with the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher, Professor Quirrell.

Quirrell informs Harry that the secret to find the Sorcerer's Stone lies within the Mirror of Erised. Harry looks into the mirror and sees himself holding the stone before putting it into his pocket. Magically, the stone actually materializes in his pocket. After lying to Quirrell about what he sees in the mirror, Quirrell unravels his turban to reveal Voldemort's face on the back of his head. Voldemort orders Quirrel to kill Harry, but unable to, Quirrel is destroyed and Harry blacks out. Upon awakening Harry is greeted by the Head Master Dumbledore. He explains to Harry that it was the power of his mother's love that prevents Voldemort from being able to harm Harry. At the end of the year feast, the trio and another fellow housemate earns Gryffindor enough house points to win the House Cup."
    </string>

	<string name="book2Summ">"Harry finds himself back at the Dursley house for summer break. He hasn't heard a single word from either of his friends, but he also cannot send letters to them because his owl is to remain caged up the entire time it's there. Restless, Harry cannot wait to get back to Hogwarts and away from his miserable muggle relatives. One day, a house elf named Dobby shows up and warns Harry that he cannot return to Hogwarts this school year. It is revealed that Harry has in fact been receiving letters from his friends, but Dobby has been intercepting them, in order to make Harry feel abandoned, hoping to persuade him to not return to school. Dobby begins wreaking havok when Harry won't promise to stay away from Hogwarts to get Harry into trouble and sabotoge his chance of returning to school.

Ron and his twin brothers show up in a flying car to break Harry out of his imprisonment at the Dursleys, and he spends the rest of the summer with Ron's family. Harry and Ron mysteriously get blocked from the entering platform 9 3/4 and end up missing the train to Hogwarts. They decide to use the flying car to just drive to school. After crash landing into the Whomping Willow, the two end up in trouble before school even starts. Trouble seems to just escalate as Harry follows a menacing voice that only he can hear, resulting in the discovery of a petrified Mrs. Norris, Argus Filch's cat. Next to her a mysterious message is written on the wall: "The Chamber of Secrets Has Been Opened. Enemies of the Heir, Beware." Professor Dumbledore says the juice from a full-grown Mandrake can cure a Petrified being, but it will take time for the Mandrakes to mature.

The students soon learn the legend of the Chamber of Secrets. Salazar Slytherin, one of the school founders, left behind secret chamber that houses a dangerous monster that only his heir can control. This evil creature specifically targets witches and wizards who were born to muggle parents. During an incident, Harry involuntarily speaks Parseltongue, the language of snakes that was spoken by Salazar Slytherin. The makes most of the school believe Harry to be the Heir and the one petrifying everyone. However, Harry, Ron and Hermione believe Draco Malfoy is the Heir. They brew a batch of Polyjuice Potion in an unused girls' bathroom haunted by a ghost named Moaning Myrtle. This will allow Harry and Ron to transform into Slytherins Crabbe and Goyle, slip into the Slytherin common room, and hear what Draco himself has to say about the situation. They find out that Draco is not the Heir, but that it was last open fifty years ago and a student was attacked by the creature and died.

Harry and Ron find a diary that belonged to Tom Riddle, a student that attended Hogwarts fifty years prior. The diary appears blank, but Harry discovers that if he writes in it, it writes back. Tom Riddle transports Harry back in time fifty years, where he witnesses a confrontation between Tom and Hagrid. Hagrid is seen protecting a creature that Tom accuses of being the one that killed the student.

Hermione is found petrified with a mirror in her hand. Harry and Ron use the Invisibility Cloak to sneak off and visit Hagrid. There they witness the Minister of Magic, Cornelius Fudge telling Dumbledore that Hagrid must be sent to Azkaban, the wizard prison. Lucius Malfoy, Draco's father, arrives, and announces Dumbledore's suspension as headmaster of Hogwarts. Hagrid's parting words lead Harry and Ron to the Forbidden Forest to meet Aragog, a giant spider. It is revealed that he is the creature Hagrid was protecting fifty year before, but he isn't the creature hidding in the chamber.

Harry and Ron are visiting Hermione is the hospital wing when they find a crushed slip of paper in her hand. From this they learn that the creature in the chamber is a basilisk, also known as the King of Serpents. They find out that Moaning Myrtle was the student killed by the basilisk fifty years ago and conclude that the entrance to the chamber resides in her bathroom. Before they can begin their investigation, Ron's sister Ginny is kidnapped and taken to the chamber.

Gilderoy Lockhart, the cowardly Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher, tries to leave Hogwarts instead of rescuing Ginny. Harry and Ron force him into a rescue mission but Harry gets separated during a rockslide on the way to the chamber. Entering the chamber alone, Harry finds Ginny near-death and the shimmering figure of Tom Riddle. Ginny found Tom's diary before Harry did and wrote all her dreams and fears in it. It was the emotion she recorded that allowed Tom to grow stronger, resulting in him possessing her to open the chamber and release the basilisk. It is revealed that Tom Riddle is the 16 year old Voldemort, peserved in the diary for the past fifty years. Admist the battle against the basilisk, Dumbledore's pheonix swoops in and blinds the basilisk after delivering Harry the Sorting Hat. From the hat, Harry draws the sword of Gryffindor and is able to kill the giant serpent. Harry ends up destroying the diary, and Tom along with it, by plunging a venomous fang from the basilisk into it. The mandrakes are now fully mature and the potion is successful in reviving the petrified students and cat. The story ends with Harry tricking Dobby's master, Lucius Malfoy, into gifting him with a sock. A house elf is bound to serve one family until it is set free by being given a piece of clothing."
	</string>

	<string name="book3Summ">"It's Harry's thirteenth birthday and he's excited to receive gifts sent by owl from his friends. However, his happiness quickly diminishes due to a visit from Uncle Vernon's sister, Aunt Marge. During dinner, Harry accidentally inflats Aunt Marge like a giant ballon after she insults Harry and his parents. Frightened he takes off into the night and is nearly attacked by a scary black dog. Saved in the knick of time by the magical Knight Bus, he boards and goes to Diagon Alley. Whilst on the bus, Harry learns of the escaped prisoner Sirius Black, the murderous wizard who once killed twelve muggles and a wizard with one powerful curse.

Harry spends the last two weeks of his vacation in Diagon Alley and is later joined by Ron and Hermione. Hermione ends up buying a cat, Crookshanks, who constantly tries to attack Scabbers, Ron's pet rat. Before leaving for Hogwarts, Harry overhears Ron's parents saying that Sirius Black is infact looking for Harry.

On the ride to Hogwarts, Dementors stop the train and their presence causes Harry to faint. These creatures are the soulless guards of Azkaban and are now guarding Hogwarts, and Harry, from an attack from Sirius Black. Remus Lupin, the new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher gives Harry some chocolate to revive him from the Dementor attack. It's noted that chocolate helps make one feel better after a run in with a Dementor. During the welcome banquet, Hagrid is announced as the new Care of Magical Creatures professor. The school year continues down a dark path, when Professor Sibyll Trelawney, the Divination teacher, informs Harry he is marked by the Grim, a dark dog omen that sybolizes death. There's more bad to come after Draco is attacked by Buckbeak, a hippogiff Hagrid introduced to the class. His father heard of this, and used his influence to call for the death of Buckbeak. Harry, Ron and Hermione help Hagrid defend Buckbeak.

Harry must stay behind while the rest of his class visits Hogsmeade, a nearby wizarding village, because he hasn't gotten permission from the Dursleys, his guardians. He ends up spending this time with Professor Lupin. The students return to find the portrait of the Fat Lady, the guard of the entrance to Gryffindor Tower, slashed to ribbons. Peeves, one of the ghosts who roam the castle, says that the culprit is Sirius Black. During a Quidditch match Harry sees another black dog before being attacked once more by Dementors. He faints once again and falls off his broomstick, which is destroyed by the Whomping Willow.

Things take a nice turn after Fred and George Weasley give Harry their prized possession, the Marauder's Map. This magical item allows Harry to sneak out of the castle and meet up with his friends in Hogsmeade. There Harry learns that Sirius Black was not only his father James's bestfriend, but also Harry godfather. It was revealed that Sirus betrayed the Potters by telling Voldemort of their whereabouts after the family went into hiding.

Harry receives a Firebolt broomstick from an unknown sender for Christmas. Worried it is a cursed gift from Sirius Black, Professor McGonagall takes it to get it inspected. It's deemed safe and Harry is able to win the final match against Slytherin. Harry has been learning the Patronus Charm for protection against Dementors, during private lessons with Lupin. Unfortunately, Gryffindor is attacked again by Sirius Black. Eventually Lupin confiscates the Marauder's Map after Harry is caught visiting Hogsmeade.

During Harry's Divination exam, Professor Trelawney suddenly predicts that a servant of Lord Voldemort will set out to rejoin his master soon. The trio go to comfort Hagrid because despite their best efforts Buckbeak is sentenced to death. After the execution, Ron is attacked by a black dog after he tries to save Scabbers from Crookshanks. The dog drags him by his leg under the roots of the Whomping Willow. Crookshanks lead Harry and Hermione down a tunnel under the Whomping Willow which comes out to the Shrieking Shack. It is here they learn that the Sirius Black is an animagus, a wizard who can take animal form, and that the black dog has been him all along. A fight between Sirius and Harry ensues, but he is unable to kill his parents' betrayer. Lupin comes in and confusingly embraces Sirius. Hermione reveals that Lupin is a werewolf and Lupin tries to explain that Scabbers is also an animagus by the name of Peter Pettigrew.

Lupin explains that James Potter, Sirius Black, Peter Pettigrew and himself were all bestfriends when they were in Hogwarts. The others became animagi in order to keep Lupin company when he took on his wolf form during the full moon. Professor Snape arrives, cutting Lupin's story short, and relishes to turn Sirius in as he holds a grudge against him. Snape is stunned and Scabbers is revealed to in fact be Peter Pettigrew. Harry finds out that it was Pettigrew who actually betrayed his parents, not Sirius. The group leaves the Shrieking Shack to turn Pettigrew over to the authorities. Sirius offers to let Harry come live with him, after his name is cleared, since he was named his godfather. Harry eagerly accepts, but the joyous moment is cut short due to Lupin's transformation, when the group emerges into the full moon night. A fight ensues, Pettigre escapes, and before Harry can receive the kiss of death from the Dementors, someone across the lake produces a Patronus charm that saves him and Sirius. Harry blacks out before the caster can be identified.

Harry awakens in the hospital wing to find out that Sirius has been recaptured. Headmaster Dumbledore is the only one who believes the trio's tale that Sirius is innocent. He tells Hermione to use her Time-Turner to go back in time and save "more than one innocent life". Harry and Hermione go back and are able to save Buckbeak from execution. It is revealed that Harry himself was the one who produced the Patronus charm. Afterwards, Harry and Hermione fly on Buckbeak to the tower to free Sirius, who flies off into the night. The book ends with a letter from Sirius giving Harry permission to visit Hogsmeade."</string>

	<string name="book4Summ">"The story begins with Frank Bryce at the Riddle house. The caretaker still lives there though the family has been dead for fifty years. One night Frank goes to investigate voices he hears only to discover Voldemort and Wormtail, aka Peter Pettigrew, plotting to find someone named Harry Potter. Voldemort kills Frank as Harry wakes up to his scar burning.

Harry is able to forget his issues with his scar as the Weasleys invite him and Hermione to the Quidditch World Cup. They travel by portkey to the tournament where they meet up with old friends. Viktor Krum, the Seeker for the Bulgarian national team, ends the Quidditch World Cup game with a dramatic capture of the Snitch. During a celebration of the match, Death Eaters, followers of Lord Voldemort, torture a group of muggles and one of them illegally conjures the Voldemort's Dark Mark in the woods.

Harry, Ron and Hermione return to Hogwarts and learn that the school is hosting the Triwizard Tournament. This is a competition between three rival European schools of witchcraft and wizardry: Hogwarts, Beauxbatons Academy of Magic, and Durmstrang Institute. However, the contest of champions will only be open to those at least seventeen years of age, much to many students' dissapointment. the contest of champions will only be open to those at least seventeen years of age. The students who are eligible put their names in the magical Goblet of Fire, which will select one champion from each school. Alastor "Mad-Eye" Moody, the new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher,
briefly turns Draco Malfoy into a ferret after trying to attack Harry. He then goes on to teach the class of the three Unforgivable Curses, including Avada Kedavra, the Killing Curse. Harry is the only wizard known to have survived the curse. Meanwhile, Hermione starts an organization called, the Society for the Promotion of Elfish Welfare, aka "S.P.E.W." The campaign was to house-elves their freedom.

The students from the other schools arrive and Viktor Krum from Durmstrang is named the first champion. The Goblet of Fire also names Fleur Delacour of Beauxbatons, and Hufflepuff Cedric Diggory of Hogwarts as the other champions. However, the Goblet sparks up again and Harry's name is produced making him the fourth champion. Harry is under the 3 years under the age requirement to participate, but is bound by the rules to do so as he was chosen by the Goblet. Most people shun Harry after this, including Ron, even though Harry insists he did not put his name in the Goblet of Fire. Things seem to get worse for Harry after Rita Seeker, a journalist, publishes a sappy profile of him in the Daily Prophet.

Each champion must complete three difficult magical tasks. Hagrid reveals to Harry that the first task involves dragons. The next day, Harry informs Cedric about the dragons since it is assumed that the headmasters of the other schools have told their champions. Moody overhears this conversation and rewards him for fair play with the suggestion that Harry uses his talent of flying to get past the dragon. Hermione helps Harry master the Summoning charm to call his broomstick to him during the task. Harry's flying skills allow him to retrieve the golden egg which ties him with Viktor for first place. The egg is a clue for the second task. Ron finally believes that Harry didn't put his name in the Goblet.

Harry learns that since he's a champion, he must attend and dance at Hogwarts Yule Ball with a date. He finally get the courage to ask his crush, Cho Chang, but she's already agreed to go with Cedric. Harry and Ron end up taking the Patil twins as last minute options and it's revealed that Viktor's date is Hermione. During the ball, Harry and Ron overhears Hagrid telling the Head of Beauxbatons, Madame Maxime, he is half giant. Cedric suggests to Harry that taking a bath with the egg will help him unravel the clue. Rita Seeker publishes an article of Hagrid's giant heritage which turns him into an outcast.

With Cedric's advice, Harry discovers that the next task involves reclaiming something from the Hogwarts lake. The night before the task Dobby gives Harry gillyweed that will allow him to breathe underwater. Harry finds Ron, Hermione, Cho, and Fleur's sister tied up at the bottom of the lake. Viktor rescues Hermione and Cedric comes for Cho. After Fleur is a noshow, Harry takes both Ron and Fluer's sister to the surface. Harry ended up outside of the time limit since he waited so long to return, but his moral fiber keeps him tied for first.

After falling asleep in class, Harry dreams of Voldemort in a room with Wormtail and wakes up with an aching scar. On Sirius' instruction, he goes directly to Dumbledore and reports the disturbing event. Harry views one of Dumbledore's memories through the Pensieve, a magical device that holds one's thoughts. He sees a trial of Death Eaters where it is revealed that Snape turned into a spy for the good wizards and the Head of the International Magical Cooperation office at the Ministry of Magic, Bartemius Crouch Sr.'s son, Barty, is put on trial.

The final task of the tournament is hedge-maze obstacle course with the Triwizard Cup at its center. The champion to reach the cup first will be declared the winner. Harry finds Viktor torturing Cedric and he rushes in to help. Harry and Cedric continue through the maze, reaching the cup at the same time. They decide to take it together, as a double win for Hogwarts. However, it is revealed that the cup is in fact a portkey, which transports them to Voldemort and Wormtail. Wormtail kills Cedric and performs a ritual to restore Voldemort's phyiscal body. Death Eaters arrive to pay homage to their Lord, with Lucius Malfoy among them. Voldemort then challenges Harry to a duel. Their spells don't work against each other since their wands both have cores with feathers from the same phoenix. Instead ghosts of Voldemort's victims spring from his wand and Harry's parents' ghosts encourage him to keep fighting. Using the Triwizard Cup Harry transports back to Hogwarts with Cedric's dead body.

Back at Hogwarts it is revealed that Barty Crouch, Crouch's son, has been posing as Mad-Eye Moody with the use of Polyjuice Potion. Harry tells Dumbledore of the events that happened after he and Cedric were transported. He explains that Voldemort used Harry's blood to revive himself, giving him the protection that Harry's mother left in Harry.

Cornelius Fudge, the Minister of Magic, is in denial about Voldemort's return. Barty Crouch is sentenced to death by the Dementor's Kiss. Dumbledore challenges Fudge's cowardly stance and informs the students of Voldemort's return at the farewell banquet. On the train ride home, Hermione reveals to Harry and Ron that Rita Seeker is an unregistered Animagus. She shows them a jar with a Rita inside in her beetle form. Harry gives his Triwizard Cup prize money to the Weasley twins so that will be able to start up the joke shop of their dreams. Harry returns home to the Dursleys and awaits his next battle with Voldemort."</string>

    <string name="book5Summ">"Harry Potter is spending his summer with his awful aunt and uncle when he and his cousin Dudley are attacked by two dementors. Harry defends himself and his cousin by casting a Patronus Charm. Soon after, Harry is visited by a group of wizards who are all members of the Order of the Phoenix. The wizards take Harry to his godfather’s, Sirius Black’s, home in London. There he learns about the Order led by Hogwarts headmaster Albus Dumbledore and its quest to fight Lord Voldemort and his followers. The Order is a secret organization that does not comply with the Ministry of Magic. The Ministry is being led by Cornelius Fudge and is not willing to believe the Dark Lord has returned. Because Harry used magic to defend himself from the dementors, he is summoned by the Ministry for a disciplinary hearing. Although underaged wizards are not permitted to use magic outside of school, Harry is not punished and free to return to Hogwarts thanks to the help of Dumbledore.

Harry returns to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry and is reunited with his best friends Ron and Hermione. Once there, he learns that Dolores Umbridge, an evil and corrupt member of the Ministry, is to be the new Defense against the Dark Arts professor. It is clear the Ministry is now becoming more involved at Hogwarts. The Daily Prophet, a wizard newspaper, keeps printing lies about Harry Potter and accusing Harry of faking Voldemort’s return. This causes tension between Harry and his fellow classmates. Umbridge refuses to teach students how to defend themselves, claiming children have no reason to learn to fight. Cornelius Fudge grants Umbridge more power and she can now inspect and evaluate the other professors at Hogwarts. Knowing the situation is becoming dire, Harry, Ron, and Hermione create Dumbledore’s Army where other students can join and learn to defend themselves from dark magic. Harry has been having dreams/visions of walking through the Department of Mysteries inside the Ministry of Magic. In his visions, he walks into a room filled with glass orbs. Harry wakes before finding out the meaning of his dream. One night, however, Harry has a vision where he takes on the body of a snake and attacks Ron’s father. Harry informs Dumbledore and the Order rescues Mr. Weasley. To protect Harry from Voldemort and these visions, Dumbledore requires Harry to begin taking Occlumency lessons with Professor Snape.

Dumbledore’s Army, meanwhile, is making great improvements as the students grow stronger. They are caught when Umbridge forces one of the members to confess. Professor Dumbledore takes full responsibility and must resign as headmaster. Umbridge takes his position as headmaster of Hogwarts. Harry has another vision where this time, it is Sirius Black that is being held captive and tortured. Hermione is concerned Voldemort may be trying to lure Harry, but Harry is too worried about Sirius to heed her warning. Harry sneaks into Umbridge’s office and uses her fireplace to transport to Sirius’ home. Once there, the house elf tells Harry that Sirius is at the Ministry. Harry returns to Hogwarts to find that his friends are being held by Umbridge in her office. Harry and Hermione lie to Umbridge, saying they were hiding a weapon in the Forbidden Forest for Dumbledore. They lead her out into the forest where they are met by a group of Centaurs who carry Umbridge away. With no time to spare, Harry and his friends race to the Ministry to try to save Sirius Black. However, after searching the Ministry for him, Harry realizes Hermione was right and it was all a trap. While searching, Harry finds a glass orb with his and Voldemort’s name on it. He grabs it and is then surrounded by Death Eaters, demanding the prophecy.

Harry and his friends use the skills they learned from Dumbledore’s Army to fight the Death Eaters. Eventually, members of the Order arrive to help them. While fighting, Harry accidentally drops the orb and it shatters. Bellatrix Lestrange, Sirius’s estranged cousin, kills Sirius and Harry is devastated to have lost what little family he had left. Dumbledore appears and fights off the rest of the Death Eaters. Bellatrix and Voldemort escape as Fudge arrives. Harry is sent back to school where Dumbledore explains the orb was a prophecy containing power Voldemort knows nothing about: Love. The prophecy goes on to explain the Harry with either destroy Voldemort or be killed by him. Dumbledore also explains why Harry must always spend his summers with the Durselys. Harry’s mother blessed Harry with her love when she died trying to protect him. This blessing can only be sealed by blood. Harry’s Aunt Petunia seals this bond by taking Harry into her home. With this knowledge, Harry returns home to his aunt’s and uncle’s for one more summer."</string>

    <string name="book6Summ">"The world is in complete disarray as Harry Potter enters his sixth year at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Voldemort and his followers are growing more powerful and wreaking havoc on both the Wizarding and Muggle worlds. The prime minister of the Muggle world meets with the past and current Ministers of Magic. It reveals that all is not well, there is a war at hand and even Hogwarts is no longer safe. Severus Snape, a professor at Hogwarts, is thought to be an enemy of Voldemort and a supporter of the Order of the Phoenix. However, he meets with Narcissa Malfoy, Draco Malfoy’s mother and wife of a well-known Death Eater. Snape makes an unbreakable vow to Narcissa and promises to keep Draco safe.

Meanwhile, Harry Potter had been spending his summer with the Durselys. Dumbledore arrives to collect Harry. The two wizards go to recruit Horace Slughorn and convince him to return to teaching at Hogwarts. Slughorn is star-struck by Harry and reluctantly agrees, claiming he had been hiding from Voldemort’s army. Dumbledore then takes Harry to the Weasleys where he is reunited with his friends Ron and Hermione. Harry and the Weasleys are shopping for school supplies when Harry spots Draco Malfoy acting suspicious. Harry follows Draco to Borgin and Burkes, where Draco is aggressively demanding Borgin fix a mysterious object. Harry now believes Draco has become a Death Eater and is working for Voldemort.

Harry finally returns to Hogwarts for his sixth year. Dumbledore announces that Professor Snape will now be teaching Defense Against the Dark Arts. This year, Harry is taking a Potions class taught by Professor Slughorn. He receives a very used Potions textbook ad inside it says the book is property of the “Half-Blood Prince”. The book is filled with notes and amendments from the previous owner, allowing Harry to do exceptionally well in the class. Dumbledore and Harry meet on a regular basis to use Dumbledore’s pensieve to observe the memories of people who had direct contact with Voldemort. Dumbledore hopes that learning about Voldemort’s past will prepare Harry for when he and the Dark Lord meet face to face. Harry learned about Voldemort’s family and how Voldemort was left at an orphanage to grow up to be a generally unpleasant boy. Most importantly, Harry learns about how Voldemort ripped his soul into seven Horcruxes. Two of the Horcruxes, Voldemort’s grandfather’s ring and Tom Riddle’s diary, have already been destroyed. This leaves five known horcruxes: something that reside within Voldemort, a snake, Voldemort’s mother’s locket, and two hidden objects.

Meanwhile, Ron begins dating Lavender Brown which causes Hermione to become jealous and create tension within the friend group. Harry begins to develop feeling for Ron’s sister Ginny. Ron and Lavender eventually break up, making Hermione very happy. Harry divides his attention between his responsibilities between being Quidditch captain and following Draco. He tries to track Draco using the Marauder’s Map, but many times cannot find him. It becomes apparent that Draco is using the Room of Requirement which transforms itself to meet the needs of whoever is using it. The room does not appear on the map which is why Harry has difficulty finding him. Harry cannot enter the room until he figures out what Draco is using it for.

Dumbledore takes Harry to retrieve Merope’s locket, the locket that belonged to Voldemort’s mother. By destroying the horcrux, Voldemort will be one step closer to mortality. Harry and Dumbledore push through a series of traps and challenges and eventually come across a basin. The locket is hidden beneath a poisonous potion. Harry fights off a swarm of Inferi, dead bodies reanimated by Dark Magic, while Dumbledore drinks the potion. The two wizards obtain the locket and return to Hogwarts; Dumbledore is very weak. When they return, Voldemort’s mark is floating above the school.

Harry and Dumbledore race to the tower beneath the Dark Mark. Once there, Dumbledore freezes Harry using magic and hides him beneath his cloak of invisibility. Draco rushes into the room and threatens to kill Dumbledore. Dumbledore is weak and his wand is out of reach. He tries to stall Draco, telling the young wizard he is not a killer and that the Order of the Phoenix could protect him and his mother. Draco begins to lower his wand and Snape quickly enters. Snape raises his wand and kills Dumbledore. When killed, Dumbledore’s spell on Harry is broken and he races after Snape to try to avenge Dumbledore. Snape escapes with the other Death Eaters and the entire school is devastated. Harry inspects the locket retrieved earlier and realizes it is not a Horcrux. Inside, there is a note from “R. A. B.”. Harry decides to not return to Hogwarts next year and will instead find and destroy Horcruxes and ultimately kill Voldemort. Ron and Hermione will join him."</string>

    <string name="book7Summ">"A group of Death Eaters are gathered at Malfoy Manner, including Snape and Voldemort himself. Snape informs Voldemort of when Harry will be moved from his aunt’s and uncle’s  home on Privet Drive to a new safe place. Voldemort plans to capture Harry while he is travelling. Harry prepares to leave Privet Drive and reads several obituaries for Albus Dumbledore. The obituaries make him question how well he knew Dumbledore and what other secrets the old wizard may have kept. Downstairs, Harry says goodbye to the Dursleys for the last time as the threat of Voldemort is forcing the muggle family to go into hiding. The Order of the Phoenix arrives, led by Mad-Eye Moody, and prepares to take Harry to the Weasleys’ Burrow. Six of the members and Harry’s friends drink a Polyjuice Potion that transforms them into Harry. The group sets out, the Harry decoys flying in all direction to try to trick Voldemort. The Death Eaters attack and Voldemort chases the real Harry down. Harry’s wand is able to fend Voldemort off.

When everyone arrives at the Burrow, they find out Mad-Eye was killed and George Weasley has been seriously injured. Harry begins having more visions; these are from the perspective of the Dark Lord himself. Harry sees Voldemort interrogating a wand maker, demanding to know why his wand was not able to defeat Harry. Ron, Hermione, and Harry prepare to set off for their quest to find Horcruxes. The new Minister of Magic, Rufus Scrimgeour, comes to deliver items from Dumbledore’s will. Harry is given the snitch he caught in his first Quidditch match as well as the sword of Gryffindor, but the sword was not Dumbledore’s to give. Ron is left with Dumbledore’s Deluminator which captures light. Hermione receives a copy of The Tales of Beedle the Bard. The trio do not know the purpose of Dumbledore leaving them these items.

The Weasleys have a wedding for their son Bill and Fleur Delacour. At the reception, Harry overhears people spreading rumors about Dumbledore such as the abuse of his sister and his possible use of Dark Magic. Death Eaters arrive and attack the wedding, indicating Voldemort has now taken control of the Ministry of Magic. Hermione, Ron, and Harry quickly Disapparate to London. They stay at the house Sirius Black left to Harry. There, they discover that the note found in the fake locket found in the previous book was left by Regulus Arcturus Black. Regulus was Sirius’ younger brother and a follower of Voldemort. Regulus stole the Horcrux and the trio recalls seeing a locket in the house but it is now gone.

Harry, Ron, and Hermione summon Kreacher, the Sirius’ house elf. Kreacher explains that Voldemort used him to test magical defenses in order to protect the locket, causing Regulus to change his mind about serving the Dark Lord. The locket had been in Kreacher’s possession but was stolen by Mundungus Fletcher. Harry orders Kreacher to retrieve Mundungus. When Kreacher returns with the thief, Mundungus says Dolores Umbridge had taken the locket. The trio disguises themselves and sneak into the Ministry to steal the locket from Umbridge. While at the Ministry, they witness the persecution of wizards who are not considered pureblood. Harry, Ron, and Hermione Disapparate back to the house but are followed by a Death Eater, forcing them to abandon the house and go on the run. They camp in the woods, trying to figure out where the next Horcrux could be and how to destroy the locket. Harry has a vision of Voldemort interrogating another wand maker, asking about a wizard who stole a wand. That night, the group overhears a goblin talking about how the Sword of Gryffindor in Dumbledore’s office was fake. Harry realizes they need to find the sword in order to destroy the Horcruxes. Ron becomes frustrated by the lack of progress and leaves the group.

Harry and Hermione travel to Godric’s Hollow. They visit Harry’s parents’ graves and the house they lived in before they were killed. They meet an old woman name Bathilda Bagshot, who invites them into her home. Harry hopes she knows enough about Dumbledore to tell him where the sword is. However, Bathilda is dead and her body was being inhabited by Voldemort’s snake Nagini. Harry and Hermione barely escape and Harry’s wand is destroyed. Harry reads a new article about Dumbledore, accusing him of working with a Dark wizard known as Grindelwald. Harry recognizes Grindelwald as the wizard Voldemort is seeking.

One night, a Patronus of a doe takes Harry to a frozen pond where the Sword of Gryffindor is buried. Harry dives in to retrieve the sword but the locket he is wearing tries to strangle him. Ron returns and saves Harry. With the Sword in hand, Ron destroys the locket. The trio of young wizards travel to the home of Xenophilius Lovegood, Luna’s father. They hope he can explain a mysterious symbol Hermione found in the book Dumbledore left her as they had seen Xenophilius wearing a necklace with the same symbol. He explains the symbol represents the Deathly Hallows: the Elder Wand, Resurrection Stone, and Invisibility Cloak. These items were created by Death and whoever owned all three was the master of death. Xenophilius signals to Death Eaters that Harry has arrived. He betrays them in the hope his daughter Luna will be released from imprisonment. Ron, Harry, and Hermione barely escape.

Later, Harry accidentally says Voldemort’s name, triggering a tracking spell. Death Eaters arrive and capture Harry, Ron, and Hermione, taking them to Malfoy Manor. At Malfoy Manor, Bellatrix Lestrange tortures Hermione, trying to figure out what how the trio got the Sword of Gryffindor since the sword was supposed to be in Bellatrix’s vault at Gringotts Bank. Bellatrix is also concerned with what else they took from her vault, making Harry believe she is also hiding a Horcrux in her vault. Dobby, the Malfoy’s old house elf, arrives and helps them escape. Dobby takes the trio along with Luna Lovegood, Ollivander the wand maker, and Griphook the goblin to Bill Weasley’s home. Harry convinces Griphook to help him, Ron, and Hermione sneak into Bellatrix’s vault. The group sneaks in, takes the Hufflepuff Cup, and escape by riding a dragon. Harry learns from a vision that the last Horcrux is hidden at Hogwarts. The trio travels to Hogsmeade, where they meet Dumbledore’s brother Aberforth who helps them enter Hogwarts. Once in the castle, Harry learns the Neville Longbottom has been organizing meetings of Dumbledore’s Army in the Room of Requirement. Harry asks if anyone can think of a hidden item that could be a Horcrux. Ravenclaw students suggest the lost diadem of Ravenclaw.

As Harry searches for the diadem, professors and students prepare to defend Hogwarts from Voldemort’s army. Voldemort and his followers attack the school, causing much death and destruction. Meanwhile, Ron and Hermione go to the Chamber of Secrets and use a Basilisk fang to destroy the Hufflepuff cup. Harry finds and destroys the diadem. Snape is killed by Voldemort, so Voldemort could have complete control of the Elder Wand (the wand belonged to Dumbledore until ownership was transferred to Snape when he killed the headmaster). Snape gives Harry his tears before he dies and Harry uses Dumbledore’s Pensieve to view Snape’s memories. Harry learns the Snape was madly in love with Harry’s mother Lily and spent his adult life spying on Voldemort and working to protect Harry. Harry also learns that part of Voldemort’s soul lives within Harry himself, making him a Horcrux. Voldemort must kill Harry before Voldemort can be killed.

Harry meets Voldemort in the Forbidden Forest and before being killed, he uses the Resurrection Stone (found inside his snitch) to talk to his loved ones. Voldemort kills Harry, but Harry wakes up in a sort of afterlife that looks like King’s Cross station. There, he finds Dumbledore who explains why Voldemort could not kill Harry. The protective charm Lily placed on Harry is also inside Voldemort because Voldemort used Harry’s blood to be reborn. Harry can now return to kill Voldemort.

Voldemort and his followers take believed-to-be-dead Harry back to Hogwarts and demands everyone else surrender. The students and professors refuse, and a final battle ensues, where Harry reveals he is still alive. Neville kills the snake Nagini using the Sword of Gryffindor, making Voldemort mortal. Harry kills Voldemort in a duel. 19 years later, Harry is married to Ginny and they are sending their children off to Hogwarts. Ron and Hermione are married and do the same with their own children."</string>
</resources>
